Sandani Gunawardhana

Software Engineering Undergraduate

sandanigunawardhana@gmail.com | +94710569459 | Pitakotte, Sri Lanka



PROFILE

I am a Software Engineering undergraduate at the University of Colombo School of Computing with strong problem-solving skills, a passion for continuous learning, and experience in full software development life cycle (SDLC). Excited to apply my skills and fundamental knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming(OOP) and Agile Methodology while being a good team player and quickly adapting to new challenges.

EDUCATION

University of Colombo School of Computing

May 2022 - Present

BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering

o GPA: 3.39/4.00

• Visakha Vidyalaya - Colombo 05

2018 - 2020

G.C.E. Advanced Level

Physical Science: ABB

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Sri Lanka Telecom - Digital Platform

Nov 2024 - Present

Intern/Software

• J.M. Wickramarachchi PVT LTD

Jan 2022 - May 2022

Trainee

PROJECTS

• ProPath: [React, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL]

Jun 2024 - Present

- A career development platform featuring personalized recommendations for CPD courses, workshops, jobs, and professional memberships, with an embedded ATS system and interview scheduling facility for companies, built using the Client-Server Architecture.
- Contribution
 - Collaborated on the UI/UX design
 - * Contributed to the frontend implementation
 - * Collaborated on the REST API design and implementation
 - * Developed and executed test cases to verify key features

StaffLink: [HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, MySQL]

Jun 2023 - Apr 2024

- A transportation platform built using the Client-Server Architecture to book vehicle seats to commute to work, with integrated payment options for daily or monthly reservations.
- Contribution
 - * Collaborated on the UI/UX design for the platform
 - * Contributed to 30% of the frontend implementation
 - * Collaborated on the REST API design and implementation
 - * Integrated email notifications using EmailJS
 - * Developed the report generation feature

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, C++, C, SQL, Scala
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS
- Libraries/ Frameworks: Angular, React, Spring Boot
- Database Systems: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Tools & Technologies: Git, Selenium, Postman, Jira, Figma, WordPress
- Soft Skills: Learning and Adaptability, Problem Solving, Analytical Skills, Teamwork, Communication

COMPETITIONS

• InspiHERTech V2.0: Winners

Jan 2024

IEEE WIE Affinity Group of SLTC

• Team 'hackHERS' secured the position of the winner of the three-phase competition

• PYHACK 2.0: 9th Place

Jan 2024

IEEE WIE Affinity Group of IIT

• Team 'hackHERS' secured 9th place in the inter-university coding competition

CERTIFICATIONS

• Scrum: The Basics Project Management Institute	Oct 2024
• AWS Educate Introduction to Cloud 101 Amazon Web Services Training and Certification	Jul 2023
• Python for Beginners University of Moratuwa	Jun 2023
• Web Design for Beginners University of Moratuwa	Jun 2023
• Advanced Certificate in English CINEC Campus	Mar 2022
• Short Course in Human Resource Management Open University of Sri Lanka	Dec 2021

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Finance Team Member

UCSC ACM Student Chapter

Feb 2023 - Present

Jan 2023 - Present

• Public Image Avenue Member

Rotaract Club of University of Colombo School of Computing

REFERENCES

• Mr. M. Giridaran

Manager Software Development

Sri Lanka Telecom

∘ mgiri@slt.com.lk | +94715364876

• Mr. W. R. N. S. Abeyweera

Lecturer

University of Colombo School of Computing

∘ rns@ucsc.cmb.ac.lk | +94768927043